[HUDSON]
Just one moment, Sherlock!
[HOLMES] Miss Hudson,
I didn't see you looming there.
Even a day as beautiful as this
is nothing compared to you.
Look at the time! Bye!
Just one moment!
Give it!
Fine!
Don't you start with me,
you no good apple thief!
[HOLMES] Please!
I just need a little longer!
Any day now, I'm sure of it!
Too bad you can't pay
rent with excuses!
If you don't have
any money, get a real job!
Otherwise, I'm kicking you out
of your room, you understand?
I do have a job, Miss Hudson!
But you know it operates
on its own schedule!
So, waiting sort of is my job.
- -[HUDSON yells]
- -[STAMFORD] Holmes!
[STAMFORD]
I thought that was you!
What a surprise seeing you
grovelling on the sidewalk.
Impeccable timing!
Miss Hudson!
This is my good friend.
You can call me Stamford, ma'am.
I work at Saint
Bartholomew's Hospital.
I'm a doctor, you see.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you!
[STAMFORD grunts]
Now that that's settled,
lend me some money.
I see. Quite the situation.
What did I do to
deserve such abuse?
Don't be cross.
It'll give you more wrinkles.
Give me more?!
I'd have nary a one if I
didn't have to deal up with you!
Now children, if I may,
it seems the logical solution
would be to find
Holmes a flatmate
with whom he
could split the rent.
[BOTH]
Hm? A flatmate?
If you're ready, I've found
some candidates for you
to consider as possible tenants.
Ahh. Like an audition.
We'll see what they can offer.
Then I'll bring out
our first victim.
Oh, and what do
I do for a living?
Just working on becoming
the next big actor.
I know! You could be my patron.
I'll pay back any rent
as soon as I make it.
Tempting, but I shall pass.
I heard you wouldn't mind
if I brought strange
men back to my room
as long as it was work
related. Is that right?
[HOLMES]
Mm-hm!
Can't imagine who told you that.
I heard something
about living free
in a house with a proper roof.
You're in a worse financial
position than he is!
Wha...?
[HUDSON growls]
You think I'm daft?
You're selecting unfit
candidates on purpose!
You planned this!
An orchestrated waste of time!
Since you're making
this so difficult,
you go find one or
you're out on the street!
[HOLMES sighs]
I've nowhere else to turn.
Please, Stamford, isn't there
anything else you can do?
Me? Well, let me ruminate.
Hold on. He might
need somewhere to stay.
[HOLMES]
Hm?
[WATSON]
Baker Street, two, two, one, B.
This is it.
That's odd. They should've
been expecting me.
[WATSON]
Beg your pardon. [grunts]
That odor. Where's
it coming from?
Excuse me, but is
anybody up there?
[WATSON]
Hello?
[grunts]
[gasps] Good lord!
Are you all right?
His pulse is normal.
Body temperature's unaffected.
Nothing's blocking his airway.
No sign of an external injury.
Yet, blood is exiting the body.
Tell me, what's the time?
[WATSON gasps]
Blast! It can't be
that late already!
Must've dozed off!
I, um... Pardon,
are you all right?
You're bleeding.
Oh, this? Just a
spot of cow's blood.
[HOLMES] Absolutely smashing!
There was a reaction!
The experiment was a success!
The what?
I've created an agent
that precipitates
when it comes into
contact with blood.
This test allows you
detect its presence,
even the smallest of
stains several months old.
[WATSON]
Hmm. Fascinating.
[HOLMES] Someday it'll be common
practice.
There's no telling the number of
murder cases
that this will end up
overturning.
Despite their similarities,
the tincture of guaiac method
is far less reliable,
requires more work, and takes
longer to give you results.
Whereas this te--
Just who are you?
Oh! Sorry.
My name's John H. Watson.
Am I safe to presume
you're Sherlock Holmes?
My friend Stamford says
that you have a room to let.
[HOLMES] Hmm. Home from
the Afghan War, Doctor?
How did you know?
Using simple deduction,
my dear fellow.
Upon discovering me,
you went to check my pulse,
then my breathing, attempting
to diagnosis my malady.
They were the actions of someone
trained in the medical arts.
Furthermore, you show
signs of a sunburn.
It'd be difficult
achieving that complexion
in London this time of year.
John H. Watson, medic
stationed in Afghanistan,
retired and retuned home.
The pocket watch
I checked earlier
is the one that is issued upon
discharge from the army.
Now you're in need
of a place to live.
But residing in a hotel
on a soldier's pension?
Obviously sharing a
flat is more practical.
Thus, why you are here.
My, good show.
Well deduced, sir.
As you've said,
I am indeed a medic
recently home
from the Afghan War.
And if I might add,
quite happily so.
Good show?
Indeed. Maybe write,
oh, something like, "My new
flatmate is bloody brilliant."
How's that?
You are an avid writer?
The ink smudges on your
right thumbnail tell the story.
[WATSON]
Yes. I am.
[HOLMES]
Well, we'd best be off.
Off? Where to?
See our landlady, Miss Hudson.
She's invited us
to dinner to conduct
a formal interview with you.
By all means, lead the way.
Also, please call me John.
All right, John.
I don't see any issue with you,
but ultimately, it's up
to dear Miss Hudson
to decide the final verdict.
A Toast to John!
And also, finally being
able to split the rent!
That's contingent upon
on whether he gets my okay.
Of course.
And we're here to discuss the
matter sensibly over alcohol.
[GROUP]
Cheers!
My, that's quite
a thirst you have.
Had a rough day?
[HOLMES]
Well, you see,
Miss Hudson's under considerable
stress for some reason.
And are you able to deduce
where the majority of
that stress comes from?!
I-I have some inkling
as to its source.
But, ma'am, still,
Sherlock does possess
an incredible talent.
Frankly,
his powers of observation
rendered me speechless.
He has a gift for perspicacity.
I know. Though, it's shame
he chooses to squander
his abilities.
When I think about how the world
won't be improved by
his cunning mind,
it makes me positively--
Just where're you going?!
Just off to the loo, mum.
Oh? Trying to run away.
I swear I'll return.
Although, if you'd prefer,
we could make it
a more communal affair.
[HUDSON gasps]
Holmes! Please!
[HUDSON] Honestly! The man
has nary a shred of decency!
If I might ask,
Miss Hudson, just what
sort of man is Sherlock?
I couldn't tell you!
On my life, I will never
understand what makes him tick.
His mind's constantly
drifting off,
thinking about who knows what.
Often, he won't come home
for two or three days,
no explanation!
Other times, he'll lock
himself away in his office,
ignoring me. The cruelty.
It is true, he can be kind
on the rarest of occasions.
[HUDSON grunts] But that
doesn't give him a pass
for acting like a child!
Which is why I must
insist his housemate
be a fully grounded individual!
[WATSON] You worry about him,
don't you, Miss Hudson?
Almost as if you were family.
[HUDSON grunts, chuckles]
Well, time to survey the damage.
Hope John's okay.
[HUDSON] You mean that
actually happened to you?
My, you really did have a
time of it on the battlefield.
Oh, no.
Nothing compared to the soldiers
who took up their rifles.
Get lost on your way back?
Um, yeah.
So you two seem like you're
getting along swimmingly.
[HUDSON] Sure. Mister Watson's
a down-to-earth gentleman,
unlike you.
[LESTRADE] Forgive me for
interrupting your festivities.
Lestrade!
Beg your pardon,
but who is this?
[HUDSON] Mister Watson,
allow me to introduce
Inspector Lestrade
of Scotland Yard.
The police?
[HOLMES squeals]
Yes! Payday has arrived!
Afraid you lost me.
[HOLMES] You see this
is my half of the rent.
Whenever the police have
a case beyond their wits,
they eventually reach out to me.
I then step in and solve it
as the world's foremost
consulting detective.
That's your profession?
Well, let's be off. No point
standing around here.
So where's the crime scene?
Walking distance
or carriage ride?
Sorry, Holmes, but this
case is slightly different.
Huh?
Tonight, at about
roughly ten PM,
the murdered body of
Lord Drebber was discovered.
Before the man died,
he left us a clue--
a message next to his body,
written in blood.
Just one word, "Sherlock."
[HOLMES]
Really?
I want you to know it gives me
no pleasure doing this.
But, Sherlock Holmes,
I'm placing you under arrest
on the suspicion of murder.
Don't make a scene.
[HOLMES laughing]
The utter genius!
The victim writing my name
in blood! That's rich!
Good show.
We were together at
the estimated time of death.
Meaning he has a solid alibi.
That's why we're
taking you all in.
Honestly, Scotland Yard's
always easily duped.
You find my name at the crime
scene and think I'm the culprit.
We'll see how long
your arrogance holds
given the mountain of evidence.
Ah. That explains it.
Who else but you, Gregson?
Nothing thrills me more
than to finally see your
smug face behind bars.
Damn bohemian.
You do realize the reason
the Yard's so
incompetent is 'cause
it's overrun with insufferable
prats like yourself?
You'll be an assistant
inspector forever
if that mystery eludes you.
[GREGSON] Show Mister Holmes
to his new quarters.
[OFFICERS]
Sir.
[GREGSON]
As for your two witnesses,
there's a few matters
we'd like to ask them about.
Take a good look.
All these were recovered
from his residence.
They belong to our suspect.
Not only are the footprints
left at the scene
the same size as Holmes's boots,
but we also found a gun
that was the same calibre
as the one used in the crime.
You know as well as I do
the suspect is a dangerous man
who caused us trouble
on numerous occasions.
It was just a matter of time
before he did
something like this.
[LESTRADE] And you swear,
you weren't responsible?
You know footprints
can be faked, Lestrade.
Not to mention the fact
my pistol's new and
hasn't been fired yet.
Should be easy
enough to confirm.
Obviously, this is
no ordinary case.
[HOLMES] Something else is
at work behind the scenes.
A huge unseen presence.
And they're still out there.
How about it? Let me see
the crime scene, Lestrade.
Just tell 'em you brought
the suspect along
to try and coax
a confession out of him.
No way. You're mad.
You really think
you can solve this?
I've no other choice.
The victim did request me
by name, after all.
[BOTH gasp]
[WATSON]
Sherlock!
Are you all right?
The assistant inspector let
Miss Hudson and myself go.
[HOLMES]
I'm glad to hear it.
I trust Gregson was bull-headed
in his interrogation.
[HOLMES]
John, I can't do this alone.
I'm going to need
your expertise.
[WATSON grunts]
Yes. Please.
I would like to ask you
for the same favor.
Ahem!
[WATSON] If I can be
of any assistance,
rest assured, I will!
Again, I appreciate
your help. Thank you.
[HOLMES]
Seems the street is lined
with aristocratic mansions.
[GREGSON] What powers
of deduction. Move along.
[LESTRADE] Welcome back to
Lord Drebber's study, Holmes.
[LESTRADE] The crime
scene's been preserved.
We haven't taken
the body to the morgue.
Right, Lestrade.
Tell me everything you know.
Victim's name:
A one Enoch J Drebber.
Born in Wales, 35 years old.
There are two maids and a butler
who live here in the mansion.
Oh, right. I forgot.
In a detached room
there's an older woman
who does the cooking.
Of the two live-in maids,
one of them planned to
rendezvous with her lover.
She was outside during
the estimated time of death.
[LESTRADE]
But despite waiting all night,
he never shows up.
Moreover, she's the one
who discovers the body.
As for the other maid,
she received word her father
had suddenly collapsed.
But when she rushed
to her parents' house,
the man exhibited no
physical ailments.
Then there's the butler
who's fond of sipping
a drink between duties.
He typically spends his
nights in his quarters
with a glass of whiskey.
Apparently, this time it was
laced with some sort of drug.
He was sound asleep when
the murder occurred.
[LESTRADE] The cook is an
older woman hard of hearing,
and once she is settled
in her room for the night,
she wouldn't notice if lightning
struck outside the window.
[LESTRADE]
Which brings us to 10:15 PM,
when the maid discovers
the lord slumped over.
In short, you're saying no one
in or around the mansion
heard the sounds of a
gun firing, is that right?
John, would you mind
inspecting the victim's body?
Certainly.
[WATSON] There are four
gunshot wounds to the chest.
And it doesn't appear to be
any signs of a struggle.
Judging by the cavities,
they were likely
caused by a pistol
fired at point-blank range.
Seems like the killer
was aiming for the heart.
Going off the amount
of blood present,
the injuries sustained
by the victim
were harmful enough
to cause him to bleed out.
[WATSON] He would've
died almost immediately.
Without further tests,
that's all I can ascertain. Uh.
Where'd you go?
[HOLMES]
Excellent work, John.
[WATSON]
Is something wrong?
[HOLMES] No. I thought there'd
be some loose change under here.
[GREGSON]
All right! On your feet, clown!
Give him a little leeway,
and this is how he behaves!
Hey, Lestrade,
would you care to hear what
conclusion I was able to draw?
Fine. I figure
even if we say no,
you'll regale us with
your genius anyway.
[HOLMES] First, there's
the writing in blood.
The earl was not the one who
wrote this. It was the culprit.
Your evidence?
It's obvious if you
look a little closer.
The width of the
lettering is clearly wider
than Drebber's bloody finger.
If you assume the
lord was the author,
he would've needed to
trace each line twice.
Hardly the behavior of dying man
with precious few seconds.
Meaning, the murderer
would have had to
have wider fingers
than the victim.
[HOLMES] It would be
the most logical answer.
Finger width is generally
proportional to hand size.
And hand size is
generally proportional
to one's physical size.
So there's a high
degree of probability
the real killer was much
larger in stature than Drebber.
[LESTRADE]
I'm listening.
Next is the manner of death.
A skilled murderer would've
put a bullet in the head.
Then perhaps after
taking careful aim,
and not missing, would've
shot the heart to be sure.
And yet,
as you can see, it's a miracle
they hit any vital organs.
[WATSON]
I had the same thought.
It appears that the shooter was
unskilled in handling firearms.
[HOLMES]
Being unskilled is one thing,
but the scattershot
approach indicates
they were firing
blindly at their target.
They ensured each of
the servants wasn't present,
arranging the perfect
conditions for the crime,
only for the actual act
to turn out muddled.
Almost as if this was
an amateur performer
playing the role of a killer
in someone else's
well-crafted script.
Basically, even though
only one individual
was responsible for pulling
the trigger on the gun,
another more capable
person set the stage,
making the crime possible.
- -[GREGSON, WATSON gasp]
- -[LESTRADE] Hold on!
In other words, a mastermind.
And someone besides the
killer came up with the plan.
[HOLMES]
Indeed. A puppet master.
The one pulling all the strings.
Perhaps...
...the same as the
case on the Noahtic.
A colossal mosaic
I'm not yet able to see.
[LESTRADE]
Holmes.
Holmes!
[HOLMES gasps]
Now then, according
to your theory,
someone instructed the real
murderer to write your name,
but why you of all people?
Ah, yes. That answer
will become evident
as soon we apprehend
them and ask.
As soon as--?! I'm sick
of all your double-talk!
Inspector!
I request permission
to interrogate Holmes!
We have our man.
I'll do whatever it takes to
make sure he confesses!
Here.
[WILLIAM] I can help
you exact your revenge.
But to do it, you'll have
to sacrifice your life.
Knowing this,
do you remain steadfast
in your resolve?
[HOPE]
Sooner or later,
I'm gonna fall victim to
this incurable disease.
My time is limited,
but none of that's important,
as long as my wish comes true.
[HOPE]
My life means nothing.
[WILLIAM] He walks alone,
death his only companion--
the best candidate
for executing this plan.
And my chance
to finally test him.
[WATSON] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"A Study in 'S' 'Act Two.'"